Finding Aid for Bay View Association records, 1875-1997
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Bay View Association records
1875-1997
Bay View Association.
8571 Bp 2
Leases, lot books, and assessment rolls; annual reports, minutes of trustees' meetings, published material, and transcripts of interviews with residents.
0.5 linear feet
43 microfilms
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The microfilming of the records was made available through the Bay View Association (donor no. 3524 ).
No further additions to the records are expected.
The record group is open to research.
Founded in 1875, the Bay View Association of the United Methodist Church is a private, voluntary membership institution. Bay View is home to more than 30 community-owned buildings, nearly 450 cottages and two inns situated on 337 acres in northwest Lower Michigan. Bay View was established as a Chautauqua-campground association of the Methodist Church at Bay View. The Association is now concerned with community affairs and the presentation of summer programs of religious and cultural content.
The records of the Bay View Association document the property within the community, including leases, lot books, and tax records. In addition, there is some annual reports, minutes of annual meetings, and minutes of meetings of the board of trustees. The Historical series consists mainly of publications and various documents important to the history of the Association.
Subjects:
Bay View Association.; Bay View (Mich.); Chautauquas--Michigan--Bay View.; United Methodist Church (U.S.)--Michigan--Bay View.MichiganBay View.
Subjects - Visual Materials:
Bay View (Mich.); Bay View Association.; Beaches--Michigan--Bay View.; Campmeetings--Michigan--Bay View.; Chautauquas--Michigan--Bay View.; Clothing and dress.; Historic buildings--Michigan--Bay View.; Historic sites--Michigan--Bay View.; Little Traverse Bay (Mich.); Resorts--Michigan--Bay View.; Swimming.; In celebration of Bay View, a national historic landmark.
Genre Terms:
Oral histories.
- Leases
  - Block 1, Lot 1-Block 15, Lot 1 (Box 1, Reel 1)
  - Block 16, Lot-Block 19, Lot 9 (Box 1, Reel 2)
  - Block 19, Lot 10-Block 22, Lot 8 (Box 1, Reel 3)
  - Block 22, Lot 8-Block 24, Lot 1 (Box 1, Reel 4)
  - Block 24, Lot 1-Block 33, Lot 10 (Box 1, Reel 5)
  - Block 34, Lot 1-Block 40, Lot 5 (Box 1, Reel 6)
  - Block 40, Lot 5-Block 45, Lot 12 (Box 1, Reel 7)
  - Block 19, Lot 23 (Box 1, Reel 7)
  - Current leases, 1965
    - Block 1, Lot 1-Block 22, Lot 4 (Box 1, Reel 8)
    - Block 22, Lot 5-Block 45, Lot 12 (Box 1, Reel 9)
  - Leases, 1965
    - Block 1, Lot 1 to Block 28, Lot 6 (Box 1, Reel 30)
    - Block 28, Lot 7 to Block 45, Lot 12 (Box 1, Reel 31)
  - Death certificates (Box 1, Reel 31)
  - Leases, 1980
    - Block 1, Lot 1 to Block 24, Lot 2 (Box 1, Reel 32)
    - Block 24, Lot 3 to Block 45, Lot 13 (Box 1, Reel 33)
    - Block 1-Block 45 (Box 1, Reel 40)
- Organizational records
  - Annual reports, 1894-1956 (Box 1, Reel 10)
  - Annual reports, 1957-1975 (Box 1, Reel 11)
  - Proceedings of annual meetings, 1876-1976
    - Michigan Camp Ground Association (Box 1, Reel 12)
    - Bay View Camp Ground Association (Box 1, Reel 12)
    - Bay View Association, 1876-1976 (Box 1, Reel 12)
  - Reports of Audits, 1957-1961; 1963-1964; 1968-1973 (Box 1, Reel 13)
  - Miscellaneous contracts (including street numbering), 1902-1929 (Box 1, Reel 13)
  - Bay View Assembly, 1888-1904 (Box 1, Reel 13)
  - Minutes of Trustees' meetings, 1875-1886; 1887-1894; 1895-August 17, 1905 (Box 1, Reel 14)
  - Court records, 1895-1915 (Box 1, Reel 15)
  - Miscellaneous information compiled by W. J. DeVol, 1915-1927 (Box 1, Reel 15)
  - Minutes of Trustees' meetings, 1905-1921 (Box 1, Reel 15)
  - Minutes of Trustees' meetings, 1921-1933 (Box 1, Reel 16)
    (include by-laws and DeVol's index to by-laws)
  - Minutes of Trustees' meetings, 1933-1935; 1936-August 1971 (Box 1, Reel 16)
  - Minutes of Trustees' meetings, 1971-September 23, 1976 (Box 1, Reel 23)
  - Proceedings of annual meetings, 1977-1983 (Box 1, Reel 38)
  - Minutes of Trustee's Meetings, June 17, 1977-September 10, 1983 (Box 1, Reel 38)
  - Minutes of Trustee's Meetings, June 1984-August 1992 (Box 1, Reel 41)
  - Minutes of Trustee's Meetings, August 1992-July 3, 1996 (Box 1, Reel 42)
  - Minutes of Trustee's Meetings, July 5, 1996-November 12, 1997 (Box 1, Reel 43)
- Lot Books, Tax Books, Miscellaneous
  - Lot Book 1, 1876-1890 (Box 1, Reel 17)
  - Lot Book (Est.), 1887-1891 (Box 1, Reel 17)
  - Lot Book 2, 1890-1904 (Box 1, Reel 17)
  - Lot Book (copy), 1890-1905 (Box 1, Reel 17)
  - Lot Book (copy) (cont), 1890-1905 (Box 1, Reel 18)
  - Lot Cash Book, 1889-1892 (Box 1, Reel 18)
  - Assessment Roll, 1902 (Box 1, Reel 18)
  - Tax roll and assessor's reports, 1902-1904 (Box 1, Reel 18)
  - Lot Book, 1905-1911 (Box 1, Reel 18)
  - Tax Assessments, 1905-1911 (Box 1, Reel 18)
  - Lot Book, 1906-1910 (Box 1, Reel 18)
  - Tax Book, 1908-1909 (Box 1, Reel 18)
  - Tax Book, 1910-1911 (Box 1, Reel 18)
  - Tax Book (cont.), 1910-1911 (Box 1, Reel 19)
  - Tax Assessment, 1911-1914 (Box 1, Reel 19)
  - Lot Book, 1912-1915 (Box 1, Reel 19)
  - Survey by Swift, 1914 (Box 1, Reel 19)
  - Tax Book, 1915 (Box 1, Reel 19)
  - Survey, Vol. 1 and 2, 1915 (Box 1, Reel 19)
  - Lot Book, 1915-1919 (Box 1, Reel 19)
  - Lot-Tax Book, 1916-1927 (Box 1, Reel 20)
  - Bear Creek Tax and Assessment Book, 1920; 1923; 1924; 1926 (Box 1, Reel 20)
  - Lot Book, 1920-1950 (Box 1, Reel 20)
  - Lot and Tax Book, 1921-1925 (Box 1, Reel 20)
  - Tax Book, 1926-1944 (Box 1, Reel 20)
  - Tax Book (cont.), 1926-1944 (Box 1, Reel 21)
  - Tax Book, 1933 (Box 1, Reel 21)
  - Tax Book, 1928-1935 (Box 1, Reel 21)
  - Lot Book and Tax Book, 1944-1965 (Box 1, Reel 21)
  - Lot Book and Tax Book (cont), 1944-1965 (Box 1, Reel 22)
  - Membership List, 1890-1944 (Box 1, Reel 22)
  - Transfer of Leases, 1905-1945 (Box 1, Reel 22)
  - Historical Collection (Box 1, Reel 22)
  - Evangelistic Association, 1896-1918 (Box 1, Reel 22)
  - Booth-Dale Park, 1904-1958 (Box 1, Reel 22)
  - WCTU, 1900-1902 (Box 1, Reel 22)
  - Tax Book, 1 B1-B22, 1965-1977 (Box 1, Reel 23)
  - Tax Book, 2 B23-B45, 1965-1977 (Box 1, Reel 23)
  - Minutes of Trustees' meetings, 1971-September 23, 1976 (Box 1, Reel 23)
  - Reports to Annual Meetings (Box 1, Reel 23)
  - Lot and Tax Book, 1923-1935 (Box 1, Reel 34)
  - Lot and Tax Book, 1944-1967 (Box 1, Reel 35)
  - Tax Books
    - 1962-1979 (Box 1, Reel 36)
    - 1980-1983 (Box 1, Reel 36)
  - Tax Records, 1979-1984 (Box 1, Reel 37)
  - Lot Books (Box 1, Reel 37)
  - Tax assessments, 1962-1979 (Box 1, Reel 29)
  - Membership and Lot Record, 1950; positive microfilm only (Box 1, Reel 39)
- Historical Collection
  - Bay View Assembly Record, 1895 (Box 1, Reel 24)
  - Bay View Assembly Herald, 1886-1889 (Box 1, Reel 24)
  - Bay View, The Summer City, 1894 (Box 1, Reel 24)
  - Little Traverse Bay Resorts (Box 1, Reel 24)
  - Golden Jubilee, 1875-1925 (Box 1, Reel 24)
  - Bay View, 1875-1950 (Box 1, Reel 24)
  - Geological Formation of L.T. Bay Region by A.W. Slocum (Box 1, Reel 24)
  - Timberland of Bay View Camp Grounds Association, Samuel J. Record (Box 1, Reel 24)
  - Bay View Herald, 1885 (Box 1, Reel 24)
  - Souvenir 25th Anniversary, 1900 (Box 1, Reel 24)
  - Department of Conservation-Woods, 1927 (Box 1, Reel 24)
  - Bishop Bowman Portrait and Library Gifts, Barclay, 1895 (Box 1, Reel 24)
  - William B. Conely letters, 1895 (Box 1, Reel 24)
  - Hall-Gordon Contract, 1908 (Box 1, Reel 24)
  - In Memoriam, Mary Hitchcock (Box 1, Reel 24)
  - Poundmaster letter, 1891 (Box 1, Reel 24)
  - Seth Reed Collection (Box 1, Reel 24)
  - Sunday School Congress, 1877 (Box 1, Reel 24)
  - F. Dudleigh Vernor Collection (Box 1, Reel 24)
  - Bay View Camp Ground, 1878 (Box 1, Reel 24)
  - Bay View Camp Grounds Association. By-laws, 1899 (Box 1, Reel 24)
  - "Beautiful Bay View" from The Detroit Conference, September 15, 1888 (Box 1, Reel 24)
  - Roscoe Sleight, "Albion College Pleiad" (Box 1, Reel 24)
  - Bay View Bulletins, 1884-1929 (Box 1, Reel 25)
  - Bay View Bulletins, 1929-1965 (Box 1, Reel 26)
  - Bay View Bulletins, 1966-1977 (Box 1, Reel 27)
  - M. Louise Jones' letter to trustees, undated (Box 1, Reel 27)
  - Bay View Notes-Mrs. G. J. Barnes from Michigan Advocate, 1888-1902 (Box 1, Reel 27)
  - Transcripts of interviews with residents of Bay View (Box 1, Reel 28)
    (positive microfilm only)
  - Miscellaneous documents (Box 1)
  - Videotape (VHS): "In Celebration of Bay View, A National Historic Landmark,", 1988; 2 copies (Box 1)
  - Microfilm collection master negative (Box 2)
    (Restricted; staff use only)